<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/amp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/amp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-15T10:09:38+00:00</updated><id>/amp/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">5 Tips to Help You Learn Coding Faster</title><link href="/amp/blog/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Tips to Help You Learn Coding Faster" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster/">&lt;p&gt;Mastering a new skill can take years of focus and practice. But what if you want to speed things up a little? When it comes to getting a job as a developer, you may not want to wait for years to get started. Good news: there are some things you can do in your spare time every day that will help you get better in less time. Here are five things to try to learn to program faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-practice-every-day-on-real-projects&quot;&gt;1. Practice every day on real projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other job, having hands-on experience is a must. Whether it’s for your own personal website or a project for a close friend or family member, try to find actual assignments to give yourself for practice. When you get to flex your coding muscles on things that will actually live on the internet, you put yourself into an immersive environment, giving you a better chance to become fluent quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-use-free-coding-websites-for-tutorials-and-projects&quot;&gt;2. Use free coding websites for tutorials and projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for aspiring developers, there is no shortage of resources online these days. Using platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;CodeAcademy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeavengers.com/&quot;&gt;Code Avengers&lt;/a&gt;, you can access free tutorials and cool project prompts. On any of these sites, you’ll work on interactive platforms, learning languages such as JavaScript, PHP, and Python to create web apps, games, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-make-and-use-flashcards&quot;&gt;3. Make and use flashcards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can handle the flashbacks to high school, go old-school and use flashcards! In the same way they helped you master vocabulary words for the SAT, flashcards can help you learn common terms for whatever coding language you’re trying to master. They’re also portable, meaning you can break them out at breakfast, on the bus to work, or when you need a five-minute break from work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have index cards handy, hate your handwriting, or are just too embarrassed to be seen holding flashcards in public, you can also use an app like &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/flashcards+-by-chegg-free/id408490162?mt=8&quot;&gt;Flashcards+&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/studyblue/id323887414&quot;&gt;StudyBlue&lt;/a&gt; to get the same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-blog-about-it&quot;&gt;4. Blog about it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to put new knowledge to the test is to try to explain it to someone else. Consider creating a personal blog to help you document your journey to becoming a masterful developer. In addition to serving as a great reminder of how far you’ve come, blogging about what you’re learning helps cement new concepts so they can connect to the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, it can also be a great way to network. By connecting with other developers, whether they’re more or less experienced than you, you have the opportunity to share what you’ve learned and take advantage of the knowledge of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a great writer? You may want to consider recording yourself and creating a vlog to share your learnings in video form instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-take-a-class-or-coding-bootcamp&quot;&gt;5. Take a class or coding bootcamp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootcamps and classes are another excellent way to learn to program faster. Classes are instructor-led, allowing students to get hands-on experience and work directly with professors. Taking the &lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/courses/web-development/&quot;&gt;Full Stack Web Development Program&lt;/a&gt; we offer at Circle Coding Academy can take you from no experience to a job-ready web developer in under a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing with your organization, changing careers, or getting serious about a hobby all starts with mastering the subject matter. If you’re a programmer or a future programmer in the Dallas area, we’d love to talk to you about how our 32-week program can help you transition into a career as a developer or sharpen your existing skills. Want to get started? Apply now &lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/apply/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-development" /><category term="coding" /><summary type="html">Mastering a new skill can take years of focus and practice. But what if you want to speed things up a little? When it comes to getting a job as a web developer, you may not want to wait years to get started. Good news: there are some things you can do in your spare time every day that will help you get better in less time. Here are five things to try to learn programming faster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now</title><link href="/amp/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript-right-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript/">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript (JS) is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackify.com/popular-programming-languages-2018/&quot;&gt;most commonly-used coding language&lt;/a&gt; for developers in 2020. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Coders from all different specialties will need a basic understanding of JavaScript to complete most designs—especially front-end designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to want to start learning JavaScript now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-technology-and-talking-plants&quot;&gt;Smart technology and talking plants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology has the potential to improve our healthcare, revolutionize our workplaces, and customize our homes. As this trend in smart tech progresses, we may find ourselves living in a sci-fi utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One appealing smart-tech project uses JavaScript code to create &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webondevices.com/the-arduino-plant-with-javascript-voice-recognition/&quot;&gt;smart plants&lt;/a&gt;. Smart plants use sensors to detect soil moisture, temperature, and other factors important for plant health. Advanced voice recognition software and text-to-voice capability makes it easy to interact with smart plants and simplifies the plant maintenance process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology is an emerging field that will soon change our lives. Learning JavaScript could provide you with the skill set necessary to land a job in this new and exciting industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drones-that-fly-themselves&quot;&gt;Drones that fly themselves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drones aren’t just fun; they’re useful, with applications in aerial photography, package deliveries, safety inspections, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virgin.com/virgin-unite/business-innovation/humanitarian-sky-drones-disaster-response&quot;&gt;humanitarian efforts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using JavaScript, it’s possible to build self-driving drones. Lines of JS code can command drones to auto-hover, perform barrel rolls, and run into red objects like a matador would do with a bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At events like &lt;a href=&quot;http://dronegames.co/&quot;&gt;Drone Games&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nodecopter.com/&quot;&gt;Nodecopter&lt;/a&gt;, programmers use software to see who can make the coolest drone. They often reuse open-source code snippets to program features like voice to text, face recognition, and advanced directional 3D movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these projects are fun, they can also help you land a job. The drone job market will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;grow faster than predicted&lt;/a&gt;, and some universities even offer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;degrees in drone technology&lt;/a&gt;. Industries that will use drones include the military, real estate, construction, filmmaking, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://uavcoach.com/uav-jobs/#guide-5&quot;&gt;insurance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about what it takes to get into the drone industry by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.ieee.org/jobs/content/Drones-are-a-big-job-opportunity-but-for-new-engin-2017-02-10&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-apps-that-dominate-industries&quot;&gt;Mobile apps that dominate industries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brainhub.eu/blog/famous-apps-built-with-react-native/&quot;&gt;Many apps&lt;/a&gt; use the JS react native framework, but the Facebook ads app is a particularly shining example. &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.fb.com/developer-tools/react-native-for-android-how-we-built-the-first-cross-platform-react-native-app/&quot;&gt;Facebook uses JS&lt;/a&gt; to calculate complex variables like ad formats, time zones, dates, and currencies. Many of these features are accessible through an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.mybridge.co/amazing-javascript-projects-for-the-past-year-v-2018-2f114c6bd70a&quot;&gt;open-source JavaScript code&lt;/a&gt;. The react native framework is also perfect for creating an integrated user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When tech giants like Facebook use JS, it shows that the language is not limited to small app projects. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/5-benefits-of-reactjs-to-brighten-a-cloudy-day&quot;&gt;JavaScript has key advantages&lt;/a&gt; that make it perfect for projects of any size. Learning JS can help developers build projects at any scale—big or small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;websites-to-inspire-action&quot;&gt;Websites to inspire action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website design skills are growing in demand. Companies spend a lot of time and money trying to drive traffic to their website. Designers who can convert that traffic into paying customers are especially competitive in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is the perfect tool for building &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdesignerwall.com/trends/30-truly-interactive-websites-built-css-javascript&quot;&gt;stunning websites.&lt;/a&gt; The code is fast, and object manipulation makes it possible to create amazing interactive designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning JavaScript will prepare you for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-web-developer/&quot;&gt;lucrative career&lt;/a&gt;, but you don’t have to wait until after graduation to get started. Working on side projects is a great way to hone your skills and build up your &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-are-companies-looking-for-in-a-web-developers-portfolio/&quot;&gt;developer’s portfolio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some amazing websites to inspire your next web-design project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://windowwonderland.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Window Wonderland&lt;/a&gt;: This website puts you right in the middle of New York City’s holiday shopping experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cavalierchallenge.com/&quot;&gt;Cavalier Challenge&lt;/a&gt;: This online game immerses you in a experience right from the get-go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airview.blueair.com/&quot;&gt;Air View&lt;/a&gt;: Air View is an innovative way to visualize abstract air quality data to make it feel “real.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyideas.net/&quot;&gt;Key Ideas&lt;/a&gt;: Key Ideas is a film-production agency that uses their website to showcase their unique skills and services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-learning-javascript-today&quot;&gt;Start learning JavaScript today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects highlight why JavaScript is such a desirable skill to have. JavaScript developers get to work on fun tasks while earning a great salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circle Coding Academy offers you the fast track to a coding career. You’ll learn the most in-demand skills from teachers who also work full-time as developers. After graduation, you’ll get access to our job placement network to connect you with the position of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to start your path towards a rewarding career? &lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-development" /><category term="javascript" /><summary type="html">JavaScript (JS) is the most commonly-used coding language for developers in 2020. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to start learning JavaScript now:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Make Time to Learn Coding</title><link href="/amp/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-to-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Make Time to Learn Coding" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-coding</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-to-code/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece was written by Erica Freedman, Content Specialist at SwitchUp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/web-developers.htm&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, Web Developers across the United States make an average of $67,990 annually. This increasingly popular career path currently has over 162,000 jobs ranging from entry to senior level. So how do you fit &lt;strong&gt;web development training&lt;/strong&gt; into your day? Use this guide to explore the field, the job opportunities associated, and offerings within Circle Coding Academy’s program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunities-after-bootcamp&quot;&gt;Opportunities After Bootcamp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web Development is an all-encompassing term that focuses on the development of websites and web applications. Jobs may include web-based internet applications, social networking platforms, and electronic business platforms. Individuals trained in this field may work in web content development, web engineering, cybersecurity, or design. This training could also lead to the development of CRM systems, still considered a new branch of web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this day and age, virtually every business and individual contractor needs a website and payment platform to operate. This means more jobs for individuals like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Growth&lt;/strong&gt;: “The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/web-developers.htm&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt; projects about 13 percent employment growth for web developers by 2026. During that period, about &lt;strong&gt;21,300 new jobs&lt;/strong&gt; will need to be filled in an industry that already &lt;strong&gt;has roughly 162,900 positions&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Developer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Web developers&lt;/strong&gt;, also called &lt;strong&gt;web&lt;/strong&gt; designers or webmasters, design and maintain websites. You might design and develop basic website layout or advanced interactive website features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Web&lt;/strong&gt; application development has certain characteristics that make it different from traditional software, information system, or computer application development. &lt;strong&gt;Web engineering&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on the specifics of application development that apply to websites and their offsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-web-development-can-boost-your-career&quot;&gt;Learning Web Development Can Boost Your Career&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Development has one of the highest job opening rates in the world.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/pictures/mjd45eilkk/web-development/#7864f8833180&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forbes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; published an article celebrating Web Development as one of the top freelance careers, with freelancers earning an average of $36 to $40 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/quora/2017/04/10/five-reasons-why-web-development-is-a-better-career-path-than-machine-learning/#378689f53ddf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have even claimed that learning Web Development is more valuable than learning Machine Learning for a few reasons: There are countless jobs, it is a simple and straightforward working process, it is creative and fun, and is also extremely lucrative. This linear career path makes room for learning new working systems and trends, while also leaving space for creative liberty and thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;circle-coding-academy-web-development-program&quot;&gt;Circle Coding Academy Web Development Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circle Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development Program is designed to take students from no experience to job-ready web developers in just 36 weeks of part-time, evening classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web 101: Intro to Web (8 Weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first course of Circle Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development Program, students will learn the basics of web development, building websites using HTML &amp;amp; CSS and learning how to deploy them to the web using Git and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript 211: Language Basics (8 Weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In JavaScript 211, students will begin to learn the basics of programming languages. They’ll learn syntax, functions, and other key JavaScript concepts that will give them the foundations for further learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript 311: Back-End JavaScript (8 Weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In JS 311 students will focus on “Back-End” JavaScript, using the Node.js framework to build back-ends. Students will also learn how to build a database and call APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript 411: Front-End JavaScript (8 Weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final coding-focused course, students will learn how to build responsive front-ends for their applications and also complete their final project – a Full Stack Web Application that they’ll be able to use in their portfolio as they begin their job search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Placement 501 (4 Weeks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, students will spend 4 weeks in Circle Coding Academy’s Job Placement Course. In this course, students will hone their resumes, develop their LinkedIn, practice whiteboarding, participate in mock interviews, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-to-take-the-next-step&quot;&gt;Ready to Take the Next Step?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 6 years, Austin Coding Academy has been serving students in the Austin area with cutting-edge curriculum and job placement services. Currently, on &lt;a href=&quot;http://switchup.org/&quot;&gt;SwitchUp&lt;/a&gt;, Austin Coding Academy has a &lt;strong&gt;5 out of 5 star rating&lt;/strong&gt; based on verified student reviews. Students find this program balanced, fair, exciting, useful and thorough. Students graduate and land great jobs all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circle Coding Academy&lt;/strong&gt; is looking to bring the successful approach that has made Austin Coding Academy the largest coding school in Central Texas, to Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to get started? Circle Coding Academy’s first cohort is launching April 13th. &lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply today&lt;/a&gt; and get on the path to a new career with Circle Coding Academy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-development" /><summary type="html">Web Developers across the United States make an average of $67,990 annually. This increasingly popular career path currently has over 162,000 jobs ranging from entry to senior level. Find out how you can fit learning to code into your day:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seth’s Journey</title><link href="/amp/blog/student-highlight/seth-davis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seth's Journey" /><published>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/student-highlight/seth-s-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/student-highlight/seth-davis/">&lt;p&gt;We had the opportunity to sit down with Austin Coding Academy alumnus, Seth, and talk about his coding journey.  He is a User Experience Developer at Indeed! He shared some insider tips and tricks for prospective and current students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Where are you from?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin, born and raised.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is your current job title?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am a User Experience Developer at Indeed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What were you doing before you signed up for ACA?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I worked in Graphic Design. That is actually what sparked my interest in coding. I sat near web developers and became curious about what they did.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How did you hear about ACA?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What inspired you to take the leap from graphic design to web development?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wanted to be involved in every process of a project. I was already proficient in HTML and CSS, so I wanted to take it a step further and dive into JavaScript.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the best thing about coding?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code is a big puzzle to solve and I love problem solving.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the best perk?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like I am finally getting paid my worth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What advice do you have to prospective and/or current ACA students?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t give up! I didn’t get a job immediately after graduation, so I spent that time sharpening my skills and networking. Make friends in the field - networking is so important!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn more about coding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our course guide or attend one of our Learn to Code events for more information!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We had the opportunity to sit down with Austin Coding Academy alumnus, Seth, and talk about his coding journey. He is a User Experience Developer at Indeed! He shared some insider tips and tricks for prospective and current students.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zollege PBC Acquires Austin Coding Academy</title><link href="/amp/blog/press-release/zollege-pbc-acquires-austin-coding-academy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zollege PBC Acquires Austin Coding Academy" /><published>2020-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/press-release/zollege-pbc-acquires-austin-coding-academy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/press-release/zollege-pbc-acquires-austin-coding-academy/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin, TX – January 2020&lt;/strong&gt; –  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zollege.com/&quot; title=&quot;Zollege Public Benefit Corporation&quot;&gt;Zollege Public Benefit Corporation&lt;/a&gt; has announced the acquisition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;Austin Coding Academy&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt;, one of the largest coding bootcamps in the state of Texas and a leader in technology education. Austin Coding Academy currently serves over 200 students in Austin and Lubbock (&lt;a href=&quot;https://lubbockcodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;Lubbock Coding Academy&quot;&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt;), providing practical and accessible technical training in software development, as well as partnering with universities and companies to source tech talent and create innovative training solutions to help build a stronger workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Coding Academy and Zollege share the same passion - debt free education. They believe an education in web development should be accessible to any and everyone who wants to learn. Beginning in the spring, in addition to Austin and Lubbock Coding Academies, new schools across Texas will open with the name, Circle Coding Academy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/&quot; title=&quot;Circle Coding Academy&quot;&gt;Circle Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt; will host its first cohort in Dallas beginning on April 13, 2020, at the Centrl Office Downtown location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another school under the Zollege umbrella is, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vandelayeducation.com/&quot; title=&quot;Vandelay Education&quot;&gt;Vandelay Education&lt;/a&gt;. Vandelay’s mission is to lead the change in the for-profit certificate market, so that the majority of certificate students will begin their career with zero federal financial aid and minimal debt. They have over 100 dental and medical schools across the nation that practice this mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Circle Coding Academy brand, and its parent, Circle Education, will join Vandelay Education as part of Zollege PBC, operating under the chartered mission of ending student debt and training the future workforce through innovative technical education. With the support of Zollege PBC, Circle Education will pursue national expansion through additional coding bootcamps, to be named “&lt;a href=&quot;https://circlecoding.com/&quot; title=&quot;Circle Coding Academy&quot;&gt;Circle Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt;”, K-12 after-school and summer programs, to be named “&lt;a href=&quot;https://earlycode.com/&quot; title=&quot;Early Code&quot;&gt;Early Code&lt;/a&gt;”, and through continued strategic partnerships with public and private entities aimed at increasing access to tech and creating innovative training solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zollege HQ&lt;/strong&gt; - home of the offices for Austin Coding Academy, Circle Education, and Vandelay Education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1335 E. Whitestone Blvd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suite W-100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cedar Park, TX 78613&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Austin Coding Academy and Lubbock Coding Academy will continue to operate normally in their respective cities, with classes continuing to be held at both Austin Coding Academy - Highland and Austin Coding Academy - Capital Factory in Austin and at the South Plains College Lubbock Center in Lubbock. Leadership at Austin Coding Academy will remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Austin, TX – January 2020 – Zollege Public Benefit Corporation has announced the acquisition of Austin Coding Academy, one of the largest coding bootcamps in the state of Texas and a leader in technology education.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lubbock Coding Academy Helps Locals Chart New Path</title><link href="/amp/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lubbock Coding Academy Helps Locals Chart New Path" /><published>2020-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/news/lubbock-coding-academy-helps-locals-chart-new-path/">&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you thought about your potential? It seems like after kindergarten graduation, school and life stopped asking what you wanted to be and instead started telling you what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most millennials, you probably aren’t happy with your current job and don’t see much potential for upward mobility or meaningful contribution… you are not alone. Millennials feel stuck - longing to create and contribute in meaningful ways but lacking the technical skills and experience to land high-paying, in-demand jobs. The disparity is even greater in non-urban areas like Lubbock, where education funding and offerings tend to lag behind larger cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequences of lower quality education lead to less developed workforce skillsets and force local employers to recruit “out of town” talent to fill the higher-paying, more skilled technology jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These developer roles offer compensation, lifestyle and meaningful contribution opportunities that are often ideal for millennials and contain the ingredients for long, happy and fulfilling careers. &lt;strong&gt;The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics reports that the median salary for web developers was $110,000 (May 2018) and the employment of software developers is projected to grow 24% between 2016 - 2026.&lt;/strong&gt; Attuned to employer demand, the rise of coding academies has begun to bridge the ‘skills gap’ in preparing people for careers in tech. However, these coding schools have been exclusive to densely populated metroplexes allotting little regard for equally talented, less industrious areas that have served as the backbone of America’s economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of innovative education opportunities and computer programming skill sets continue to place rural workers and employers in a bind. Workers are willing to learn new skills to qualify for jobs in technology, but local employers can’t front the cost of building and teaching a curriculum that delivers the necessary skills for success in these roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensing rising frustrations and witnessing a constant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.listenmoneymatters.com/what-is-brain-drain/&quot;&gt;“Brain Drain”&lt;/a&gt; of local Lubbock talent to urban cities, Texas Tech commissioned Austin Coding Academy to equip Lubbock area workers with the coding skills to win rewarding careers in technology here at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy (now a partner with the Lubbock Economic Development Association (LEDA), South Plains College and Texas Tech University) provides ‘full-stack’ coding education and skill development through part-time, in-person classes allowing students to keep their day jobs while gaining the skills to upgrade careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32-week program meets twice a week in the evenings and consists of four 8 week classes taught by full-time developers who know exactly what it takes to succeed in a career in tech. Students have access to unlimited one-on-one tutoring sessions, Saturday study groups and initiate countless meetups at local libraries and coffee shops to understand the nuances of their new highly valuable skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy’s coding curriculum is completely customized to the request of 12 of Lubbock County’s largest employers (including Tyler Technologies, SitePro, Texas Tech &amp;amp; many others) who as a group have stated &lt;strong&gt;they plan to hire 50 - 100 developers in each of the next five years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lubbock Coding Academy (LCA) graduates are finding themselves in the perfect position to secure these careers thanks to their ‘full-stack’ education and access to LCA’s &lt;strong&gt;Job Placement Program&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to the 32-week curriculum, LCA offers students a free four-week job placement course where they work on best practices for resume building, participate in mock interviews and whiteboarding sessions, and attend networking events with local employers and LCA partners. Additionally, LCA’s placement and partnerships department takes initiative to connect recent graduates with jobs in technology and boasts a &lt;strong&gt;91% placement rating&lt;/strong&gt; graduating alumni to tech giants like Facebook, Amazon, and IBM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February of 2019, the first group of 20 Lubbock County residents began their journey to a better life. After completing all four instructional modules and the Job Placement module at the Texas Tech Innovation Hub, &lt;strong&gt;every Lubbock Coding Academy program graduate has been successfully placed in a new career in technology.&lt;/strong&gt; Since the first cohort launch in February 2019, four more cohorts have launched in Lubbock’s Full Stack Web Development Program and are on their way to new careers in technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LCA has seemed to strike a chord in Lubbock County. People of all types are excited about becoming students again and improving their skills and career possibilities. Local officials and employers are also backing the LCA partnership as a means to enhance a workforce that has previously been underestimated by outside investors. In time, Lubbock may prove to be fertile ground for new business and start-up investment, and now with a growing population of software developers and computer programmers, they won’t have to go far to find good help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Lubbock County resident who is looking to break away from the pack and chart your own path, you may be a good candidate for a career in technology through Lubbock Coding Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Lubbock Coding Academy’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://lubbockcodingacademy.com/web-dev/&quot;&gt;web development curriculum&lt;/a&gt; and class start dates, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lubbockcodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply online&lt;/a&gt;. We are currently enrolling students for our next cohort.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Lubbock Coding Academy is helping the people of Lubbock launch new careers in Lubbock's growing technology industry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY &amp;amp; WP ENGINE LAUNCH WORDPRESS FUNDAMENTALS COURSE AND JOB OPPORTUNITIES</title><link href="/amp/blog/press-release/austin-coding-academy-wp-engine-partnership/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY &amp; WP ENGINE LAUNCH WORDPRESS FUNDAMENTALS COURSE AND JOB OPPORTUNITIES" /><published>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/press-release/ustin-coding-academy-wp-engine-launch-support-wordpress-fundamentals-course-and-job-opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/press-release/austin-coding-academy-wp-engine-partnership/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE: 10/28/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin, TX – October 2019:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Austin Coding Academy (ACA) and WP Engine today announced an ongoing collaboration to launch an in-person&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/wordpress-fundamentals/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals course&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to train students in core WordPress elements and develop the technical proficiencies necessary to become a technical support specialist with WP Engine. In addition to providing this technical training, WP Engine will guarantee an interview with every student who completes the course to explore career possibilities with WP Engine. Qualified graduates will interview at WP Engine for an L1 Support Technician position. All WP Engine employees will enjoy competitive compensation, health benefits, paid time off, family leave, 401k with match, equity, ongoing training &amp;amp; development and much more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Central to Austin Coding Academy’s mission is continuing to increase access to careers in technology in Austin through thoughtful technical training and to create innovative employment and training solutions for tech companies. “This course, in collaboration with WP Engine, is an opportunity to train for an in-demand skill while also providing students with a unique opportunity to launch their career with a top tech company here in Austin,” says Austin Coding Academy CEO, Chris Lofton. “We’re also excited to collaborate with WP Engine to provide an innovative hiring solution to fuel their continued growth.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are excited to collaborate with Austin Coding Academy,” said Brian Ferguson, Senior Director, Talent Acquisition at WP Engine. “We feel this partnership will help build a community of WordPress experts while adding another channel for growth for our Customer Experience team.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WP Engine and Austin Coding Academy will be launching the first WordPress Fundamentals cohort in early 2020, with classes to be held at Austin Coding Academy – Highland Campus (314 E Highland Mall Blvd, Austin, TX 78752). The key features of the program include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;10 weeks of instruction, consisting of part-time, evening courses taught by a professional WordPress Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlimited tutoring included in tuition for all students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A practical, project-based curriculum that covers a wide range of WordPress fundamentals, as well as the opportunity to interface with WP Engine Recruiters and interview for a Technical Support role&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, contact the above representatives, visit the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/wordpress-fundamentals/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals Course Page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;or join Austin Coding Academy and WP Engine at the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/austin-coding-academywp-engine-launch-event-happy-hour-wp-engine-tickets-78066889167&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WordPress Fundamentals Launch Event&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Thursday, November 14th at WP Engine (504 Lavaca St, Austin, TX 78701).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eric Jones, VP, Global Communications, WP Engine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:press@wpengine.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;press@wpengine.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Lofton, CEO, Austin Coding Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:clofton@austincodingacademy.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clofton@austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Austin Coding Academy:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin Coding Academy is Austin’s source for innovative tech talent and education. Our mission is to make careers in technology accessible to everyone through practical and equitable technical training, and to provide innovative solutions and training to tech companies. Learn more about ACA here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;https://austincodingacademy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About WP Engine:&lt;/strong&gt; WP Engine is the WordPress Digital Experience Platform that gives companies of all sizes the agility, performance, intelligence, and integrations they need to drive their business forward faster. WP Engine’s combination of tech innovation and an award-winning team of WordPress experts are trusted by over 120,000 customers across 150 countries to provide counsel and support, helping brands create world-class digital experiences. Founded in 2010, WP Engine is headquartered in Austin, Texas, and has offices in Brisbane, Australia; Limerick, Ireland; London, England; Omaha, Nebraska; San Antonio, Texas; and San Francisco, California.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Austin Coding Academy and WP Engine today announced an ongoing collaboration to launch an in-person “WordPress Fundamentals” course to train students in the technical proficiencies necessary to become a technical support specialist with WP Engine and provide a guaranteed interview. Learn more:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY &amp;amp; AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY PARTNER TO LAUNCH TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY CODING ACADEMY</title><link href="/amp/blog/press-release/texas-tech-and-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY &amp; AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY PARTNER TO LAUNCH TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY CODING ACADEMY" /><published>2019-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/press-release/texas-tech-university-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/press-release/texas-tech-and-austin-coding-academy-partner-to-launch-texas-tech-university-coding-academy/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE: 9/17/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin, TX – September 2019:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy (ACA) today announced an ongoing partnership to launch “Texas Tech University Coding Academy”, a part-time web development program that prepares students for careers as web developers and software engineers. Texas Tech University Coding Academy will launch its first cohort at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes in early 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austin Coding Academy’s mission is to increase access to careers in technology through thoughtful technical training and to create innovative employment, training, and education solutions to meet the needs of the growing tech industry. “Texas Tech Coding Academy represents a great opportunity for Austin Coding Academy to partner with one of Texas’ premier public universities to provide an innovative education solution for communities around the state,’’ says Austin Coding Academy CEO, Chris Lofton. “We’re looking forward to launching the program at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes, and finding ways that we can make Texas Tech Coding Academy work for the community of Marble Falls and surrounding areas.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Texas Tech University has offered academic degree programs in Marble Falls for several years. However, the certificate programs being taught through the Texas Tech University Coding Academy is a new offering. It is exciting to be able to offer this opportunity for individuals in the Highland Lakes area,” says Dr. Melanie Hart, Vice Provost for eLearning and Academic Partnerships at Texas Tech University.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy will be launching the first Texas Tech University Coding Academy cohort in early 2020, with classes to be held at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes (806 Steve Hawkins Pkwy, Marble Falls, TX 78654). The key features of the program include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;32 week, part-time instruction developing Full Stack Web Development skills, with a focus on JavaScript&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlimited tutoring included in tuition for all students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A practical, project-based curriculum that prepares students to be professional web developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, contact the below representatives, or join Austin Coding Academy and Texas Tech University at a public signing on September 18th at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes or visit texastechcodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay Taylor Ed.D, Senior Director, Texas Tech University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Clay.Taylor@ttu.edu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay.Taylor@ttu.edu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Lofton, CEO, Austin Coding Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:clofton@austincodingacademy.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clofton@austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Texas Tech University:&lt;/strong&gt; The Texas Tech University System was formed in 1996 and formally established by the State of Texas three years later in 1999. Since its inception, the TTU System has emerged as one of the top public university systems in the nation and is a dynamic force in higher education. Today, the TTU System consists of four component institutions and operates at multiple campuses and academic sites across the state and globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Austin Coding Academy:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin Coding Academy is Austin’s source for innovative tech talent and education. Our mission is to make careers in technology accessible to everyone through practical and equitable technical training and to provide innovative solutions and training to tech companies. Learn more about ACA here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;https://austincodingacademy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Texas Tech University and Austin Coding Academy (ACA) today announced an ongoing partnership to launch “Texas Tech University Coding Academy”, a part-time web development program that prepares students for careers as web developers and software engineers. Texas Tech University Coding Academy will launch its first cohort at Texas Tech University at Highland Lakes in early 2020.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Austin Coding Academy Student Highlight: Greg Swan</title><link href="/amp/blog/student-highlight/greg-swan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Austin Coding Academy Student Highlight: Greg Swan" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/student-highlight/austin-coding-academy-student-highlight-greg-swan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/student-highlight/greg-swan/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-to-know-austin-coding-academy-graduate-greg-swan&quot;&gt;Get to know Austin Coding Academy graduate Greg Swan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy, we take pride in the success that our students and graduates achieve. Every month we look to highlight at least one of our graduates and let the world know about what they’re doing in their new careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we caught up with Austin Coding Academy graduate &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Greg Swan&lt;/a&gt;, who accepted a job as a Web Developer at Kinetic Theory in Austin after finishing our Full Stack Web Development Track in 2018. Greg now works as a Web Application Developer with OpenSymmetry. Here’s what he had to say about his experience as an Austin Coding Academy student:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-austin-coding-academy-prepare-you-for-the-job-market&quot;&gt;How did Austin Coding Academy prepare you for the job market?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA prepared me for the job market the way a high school teacher prepares you for college; they gave me a solid foundation of knowledge, taught me what not to do, and consistently reminded me that there was a job out there for me if I was willing to put in the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;did-aca-help-you-on-the-job-search&quot;&gt;Did ACA help you on the job search?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! Chris Lofton was a great a help as far as finding and landing my first job. He recommended me to so many employers, and was a big part of how I got my initial interview for my current position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-advice-for-current-or-future-aca-students&quot;&gt;Any advice for current or future ACA students?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcswan.github.io/Resume/&quot;&gt;A portfolio&lt;/a&gt; is helpful and can help you find a job, but I think it was also helpful to build one more website. &lt;strong&gt;Also: the more you code, the better you get.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;share-a-fun-fact-about-yourself&quot;&gt;Share a fun fact about yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up in the middle of the night and eat ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-learn-more&quot;&gt;Want to learn more?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about why Austin Coding Academy is the perfect place to launch your coding career, download our course guide below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;schedule a Q&amp;amp;A with us today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sudent-highlight" /><summary type="html">This month, we caught up with ACA graduate Greg Swan, who accepted a job as a Web Developer at Kinetic Theory in Austin after finishing the JavaScript track. Greg now works as a Web Application Developer with OpenSymmetry. Here's what he had to say about his experience as an Austin Coding Academy student:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Ways a Coding Bootcamp is Worth It</title><link href="/amp/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Ways a Coding Bootcamp is Worth It" /><published>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/amp/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="/amp/blog/web-development/4-ways-a-coding-bootcamp-is-worth-it/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-after-graduation-4-ways-a-coding-boot-camp-is-worth-it&quot;&gt;What’s After Graduation? 4 Ways a Coding Boot Camp Is Worth It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since coding academies have become an increasingly visible part of the tech landscape over the last half-decade, more schools have cropped up with more coders graduating every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While job placement statistics for bootcamp graduates have been fantastic since the schools came into existence, there’s still a growing sense among some that enrolling may not be worth it. With so much new popularity, it’s fair to ask if a coding boot camp is worth it. In fact, we’re going to ask it (and explore it) even more directly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the market for coders reached saturation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to answer this question, we’re going to explore what life is really like after graduating from a coding boot camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a coding bootcamp ourselves, this information is extremely important to us, so we make sure our sources on the tech industry and employment statistics are as thorough and current as possible. So let’s see why coding bootcamp might be right it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coding-graduates-make-excellent-money&quot;&gt;Coding Graduates Make Excellent Money&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding bootcamps are an investment. There’s a lot of earning potential afterwards, but there’s also the cost of tuition to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, getting a bachelor’s in computer science from a university is a four-year process, and it doesn’t come cheap. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.collegecalc.org/majors/computer-science/&quot;&gt;estimated average for a four-year computer science degree&lt;/a&gt; is $167,968. Associate programs take two years, and the average cost is $41,568. By comparison, a coding academy is a fraction of the cost, and the courses span weeks or months instead of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though coding classes are cheaper and faster, the earning potential is the same. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursereport.com/blog/salaries-after-coding-bootcamp&quot;&gt;study by Course Report&lt;/a&gt; found that the average bootcamp graduate makes a starting salary of $70,698 annually. Plus, as the tech industry continues to grow, that earning potential will keep growing with it. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/careers/best-jobs/software-developer/salary&quot;&gt;median pay&lt;/a&gt; for software engineers is already $101,790, and the top 25% of earners make an average of $128,960. So if you’re in it for the money, going to a coding bootcamp is definitely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bootcamp-graduates-get-hired&quot;&gt;Bootcamp Graduates Get Hired&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, starting salaries don’t apply to graduates who don’t get hired, but coding bootcamp graduates have around a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hyperiondev.com/index.php/2019/03/04/will-i-get-a-job-after-a-coding-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;90% job placement average&lt;/a&gt;. A huge portion of these jobs exists because of the healthy growth in the programming industry. In fact, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;United States Bureau of Labor&lt;/a&gt; predicts that the availability of software developer jobs is growing at 24%, which is way higher than jobs in other industries. Because the tech industry and the coding industry are growing together, they both get perks from finding job opportunities with new graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those hiring statistics only improve when the coding bootcamp has industry connections (like us). At Austin Coding Academy, we stay plugged into the local tech industry to keep expanding our network across the nation. Our curriculum is even built for and with hiring companies, meaning that you learn exactly what you need to get hired after graduating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-coding-bootcamp-sets-you-up-for-many-different-tech-jobs&quot;&gt;A Coding Bootcamp Sets You Up for Many Different Tech Jobs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people worry that certain coding classes will only set you up for certain jobs, but the truth is that a lot of tech jobs require solid coding know-how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Careers can change depending on the company and industry, but our graduates have found career fits as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software engineers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full stack developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product architects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project managers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UX developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding Instructors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of versatility in coding, which attracts students from all walks of life. Whether you’re supplementing existing skills, wanting a total career change, or just want to strike out on your own, we help our bootcamp students find opportunities they’ve never thought of before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-companies-hire-from-coding-academies&quot;&gt;Important Companies Hire from Coding Academies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big names in the tech industry recognize the value of bootcamp graduates. Our former students have found work with Dell, IBM, Dosh, Plural Sight, Oracle, Adobe, and more. Or, if you want to go in the opposite direction, start-ups are always looking for fresh talent, to the point where they often hire right out of bootcamps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, 72% of employers find that coding boot camp graduates are just as competent as university graduates. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.indeed.com/2017/05/02/what-employers-think-about-coding-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;Some hiring managers&lt;/a&gt; even prefer boot camp graduates to university computer science majors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find a job worth having in the technology industry, you need to learn how to code before you can do much else. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/web-development/&quot;&gt;Full Stack Web Development Program&lt;/a&gt; is designed to teach you the skills you need to ultimately get the job you want. In other words, our job isn’t done until you have your job.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since coding academies have become an increasingly visible part of the tech landscape over the last half-decade, more schools have cropped up with more coders graduating every year. With so much new popularity, it's fair to ask if a coding boot camp is worth it. In fact, we’re going to ask it (and explore it) even more directly:</summary></entry></feed>